DAVID RYAN

<u>daveryan145@gmail.com</u> | 630-731-6796 github.com/dave-ryan | <u>linkedin.com/in/davidryan600</u> | <u>dave-ryan.github.io</u>

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Covering the full stack experience from planning to coding to hosting, I simply love to create new things. Building new tools to create a web experience that I would love if I were a user is a huge driving factor in my work, and that passion also fuels my hobby projects.

SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, Vue.js, React.js, Knockout.js, C#, .NET, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git, Github, Bootstrap, Azure, Azure Devops, Deployment

EXPERIENCE

Perkspot | Technical Support Engineer

May 2022 - Present

- Build tools for clients to use, including a robust modal to allow clients to upload confidential data and edit the data in-browser for a more user-friendly experience
- Front-line for all site issues/bugs. Investigate and solve data/code issues involving Finances, Data Erasure, Backend, Frontend, Product Inventory, Email Templating & Sending, Reporting, and more. Coordinate and escalate issues when necessary
- Support DevOps with Azure configuration, bi-weekly Deployments, Automation, and site maintenance

Hospitality Logistics International | Carrier Sales Support Rep

July 2019 - August 2021

- Programmed script shortcuts and customized advanced app settings for email automation, improving internal communication and efficiency
- Tracked location and status of truck shipments across the US, identifying potential delays and communicating them to clients

Visual Pak Logistics | Dispatch Coordinator

November 2017 - April 2019

- Created and maintained a spreadsheet of frequently used trucking companies and their preferred routes to maximize sales potential
- Minimized costs and increased supplier options by researching trucking companies and negotiating pricing for services

EDUCATION

Actualize | Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

July 2021 - November 2021

- Bootcamp: Learned fundamentals and best practices in full-stack web development in areas of project architecture, backend, frontend, and how to effectively self-teach new technologies
 - Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schema, and researched outside resources
 - Built and tested the backend, incorporating external APIs
 - Created pages and RESTful routes, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styled results, incorporated libraries and themes